Is it something that people believe?
A fact is anything that can be proved.
For example, it can be proved that China has more people than any other country in the world.
This is a fact.
Then what is an opinion?
An opinion is what someone believes is true but has not been proved.
So an opinion is not good evidence in a trial.
For example, it is an opinion if you say "Cats are better pets than dogs".
It may be true, but it is difficult to prove.
Some people may not agree with this opinion but they also cannot prove
that they are right.
In a trial, a judge must decide which eyewitnesses to believe
and which not to believe.
The judge does not consider what each eyewitness looks like or where
that person lives or works.
This kind of information is called evidence.
In April 1945 I heard something explode at midnight.
I got up and ran outside.
The sound came from a mine that hadn’t been used for a long time.
Suddenly I saw some German soldiers by the light of the moon.
They were taking wooden boxes from trucks and putting them in the mine.
A week later I decided to go and see for myself.
To my surprise the entrance to the mine was closed.
Some people say that the Amber Room and some gold were buried in the mine.
I think it might be so, as the Amber Room has never been found.